Sam Alexander Celani

github.com/alexander-the-alright • (810)683-4581 • sacelani@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Recent university graduate with 3+ years of hardware and software development experience. Possess a bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering, with a strong focus on communication systems and embedded programming. Looking to utilize my skills and knowledge in a new position in my field.

EDUCATION

Michigan Technological University - Houghton, MI

August 2014 – May 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering Department GPA: **2.91** | Cumulative GPA: 2.87

Outstanding Teaching Award

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Vice President, Wireless Communications Enterprise

Bird Sensor Team – **Project Engineer**

- Created a low-cost, low-maintenance sensor to aid in a time study of bird strikes on windows
- Primarily in charge of programming (Arduino)

Translation Lookup Pairs – Personal Project

github.com/alexander-the-alright/TLPr.git

- Personal project developed to help myself learn Russian
- Dictionary-based data structure, separated syntactically for specially formatted output
- CLI for grammar help menu and add/edit/delete 'Eng -> Rus' pairs
- Basic Italian port github.com/alexander-the-alright/TLP.git
- Metadata for topic-based searching and word dumps

WORK EXPERIENCE

Advanced Power Systems Research Center - Calumet, MI

May - August 2018 and 2019

APRA-E Project: NEXTCAR - Research Assistant/Intern

- Developed software for wireless V2V, V2C, V2I, and C2V communications using AMQ Protocol
- Intelligently redesigned routing topology for efficient, cycle-free, robust communication
- Developed ease of access tools for navigating the terminal
- Used Simulink, Python (pika module), RabbitMQ (message broker), Cohda DSRC (V2I transceiver)

US Manufacturing – Warren, MI

June 2016 – August 2016

Continuous Improvement – **Quality Intern**

- Managed daily line defect sheets and Pareto of Defects for several manufacturing lines
- Introduced new system for organizing defect sheets

Elec/Comp Learning Center Coach – Houghton, MI	Jan 2018 – May 2021
Embedded Systems Interfacing (EE4737) TA – Houghton, MI	Jan 2020 – May 2020
Hardware-Software Integration (EE3173) TA – Houghton, MI	Sept 2020 – May 2021
Electronics (EE3131) TA – Houghton, MI	Jan 2021 – May 2021

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Microcontrollers
- CLI Programming
- Quartus, Qsys, and AMP
- Algorithmic Design/Analysis
- Unix and Windows Development

- Embedded Programming
- IAR Workbench
- Microsoft Office
- Software Testing
- Basic Analog Control Theory/Design

LANGUAGES

Fluent	Proficient	Familiar	Learning
 Python 	 Assembly 	• Go	 Rust
 Java 	• C++	Bash/Batch	 Russian
• C	 MatLab 	• Verilog	 Norwegian